이 치즈 케이크
좀 먹어봐
You have got to try this cheesecake.
난 단 거 별로
안 좋아하는데...
You know, I'm not that much
of a sweet tooth..
와, 정말 촉촉하다!
Oh, my God, it's so creamy!
내가 먹어본
치즈케이크 중 최고야!
That's the best
cheesecake I've ever had!
어디서 난거야?
Where did you get this?
집에 오니 문 앞에 있던데
누가 보냈나봐
It was at the front door when I got
home. Somebody sent it to us.
너희집 주소 아닌데
This isn't addressed to you.
아래층의 브레이버맨
부인한테 온 거잖아!
This is addressed
to Mrs. Braverman downstairs!
도둑!
Thief!
상자를 연 다음에
주소를 봤는데
I didn't read the box
before I opened it...
이미 연 걸
돌려줄 수도 없잖아
and you can't return a box
after you opened it!
- 왜 안 돼?
- 너무 맛있으니까!
-Why not?
-Because it's too delicious!
이건 도둑질이야
그럼 안 되지
You stole this cheesecake.
That's wrong.
아냐, 브레이버맨 부인은
새로 받을 거니까
No, it'll be okay because Mrs. Braverman
will send for a free one.
누이좋고 매부좋고지
That way, we all win.
손해보는 건
큰 치즈케이크 회사뿐이지...
The only losers are the
big cheesecake conglomerate...
'엄마 빵집'이라고 하는
"Mama's Little Bakery."
정말 찔린다
I feel terrible.
난 정말 형편없는
인간이야
I'm a horrible, horrible person.
뭐라고?
I'm sorry, what?
The One With All The Cheesecakes
I should get going. Big day at work.
가봐야겠어
오늘 중요한 날이야
You know how I'm in a coma?
나 혼수 상태잖아
Today they do a test on me and it
turns out I'm not brain-dead.
오늘 테스트를 해보고
뇌사가 아니란 걸 알아내
So..
그래서...
Mr. Smarty Pants.
잘난 척 도사
It's just my character
that's not brain-dead.
뇌사가 아닌 사람은
극중 인물이야
Phoebe, still on for tonight?
피비, 오늘 약속 변함없지?
-Absolutely.
-I'll see you at 8.
- 그럼
- 8시에 보자
What's at 8?
8시에 뭐해?
Dinner. We get together about once
a month to discuss the rest of you.
저녁 먹어, 한 달에 한 번씩
만나 너희들 얘기하거든
Wow! Did not know that.
와! 금시초문이네
May I say how lovely you look today?
너 오늘 정말 예쁘다
Duly noted.
잘 기억해 두지
zSo for tomorrow, do you want to
rent a car and drive down together?
그럼 내일 차 렌트해서
같이 내려갈까?
-What are you talking about?
-Cousin Frannie's wedding.
- 무슨 소리야?
- 사촌 프래니 결혼식 말야
You were invited?
오빤 초대받았어?
No.
아니
Oh, my God, I can't believe this.
맙소사, 어떻게
이럴 수가 있지?
엄마, 아빠만
초대받은 줄 알았는데
I thought only Mom and Dad
were invited.
7살부터 9살까지
프래니와 난 단짝이었거든
From the ages of 7 to 9,
Frannie and I were inseparable.
9살 이후로 프래니가
새 친구를 사귀었나 보네
Maybe since the age of 9,
Frannie's made some new friends.
It's probably just a mistake.
Let me call Aunt Cheryl.
뭔가 착오가 있었겠지
숙모한테 전화해볼게
네 초대장이 어디서
없어졌을 지도 모르잖아
Maybe you are invited and the
invitation got lost in the mail.
숙모한테 전화하면
당신 귀여운 딸내미께서
You call her and tell her
that when we were kids...
어렸을 때 몇 번이나
내 옷 벗기려 했었다고 전해
her precious Frannie
tried to undress me several times.
내가 안 말렸더라면
지금쯤 결혼식 할 일도 없을걸
If I hadn't stopped her, there
wouldn't be a wedding to go to.
내 옷도
벗기려고 했는데
She tried to undress me too.
난 우리 사촌, 글렌
옷 벗겼었는데
I used to undress my cousin Glenn.
조셉 프랜시스 트리비아니
집에 있어?
Joseph Francis Tribbiani,
are you home yet?
아직 안 왔어, 왜 그래?
I think he's still out.
What's wrong?
말해주지, 레이첼 캐런 그린
I'll tell you, Rachel Karen Greene.
둘이 약속이 있었는데
이 메모만 남기고 안 왔어
I had plans with Joey,
and he left me this note.
'피비, 못 가겠어
데이트가 있거든'
"Phoebe, can't make it.
Got a date. Talk to you later.
'빅 대디'
Big Daddy."
- '빅 대디'?
- 우리끼리 쓰는 별명이야
-"Big Daddy"?
-That's a nickname we were trying.
내 별명은 못 들어봤지?
'로사트론'
You know what nickname
never caught on? "The Ross-a-tron."
조셉 프랜시스 왔구나!
Here's Joseph Francis!
잠깐, 왜 중간이름까지
부르고 난리야?
Wait, what are you
middle-naming me for?
메모 남겼잖아
I left you a note.
그렇다고
날 바람맞추면 안 되지
That doesn't give you the
right to ditch me!
누구랑 잘 가능성이 있으면
친구와 약속 취소해도 돼
You can cancel plans with friends
if there's a possibility for sex.
맞아, 그게 규칙이야
He's right. That is the rule.
난 인정 못 해
약속을 했음 지켜야지
I don't accept it. When we make
plans, I expect you to show up.
I'm not a way to kill time
till you meet someone better.
더 좋은 사람 만날 때까지
심심풀이 땅콩이 되긴 싫어
Boyfriends and girlfriends will
come and go, but this is for life.
애인은 만났다 헤어지지만
친구는 영원한 거야
I'm so sorry. I had no idea
it would bother you this much.
미안해, 그렇게
화낼 줄 몰랐어
Well, it does.
화나 죽겠어
Well, can I make it up to you?
어떻게 해주면 될까?
I'm sorry.
미안해
How about dinner tomorrow night?
I'll pay for myself.
내일 저녁 어때?
내건 내가 낼게
Okay, you wore me down.
좋아, 봐준다
While you're over there, how
about a beer for "The Ross-a-tron"?
'로사트론'한테
맥주 한 병 갖다 줄래?
"Ross.." Is that back?
그 별명 또 쓰는 거야?
The other cheesecake came.
치즈케이크가 또 왔어
They delivered it here again.
또 여기로 배달됐어
Just bring it downstairs.
What's the problem?
그럼 갖다 줘
뭐가 문제야?
I can't seem to say goodbye.
작별인사를 할 수가 없어
Are you serious?
진심이야?
We ate an entire cake
two days ago and you want more?
이틀 전에 케이크 하날
다 먹고 또 먹고 싶어?
Well, I've forgotten
what it tastes like.
맛이 어땠는지
잊어 버렸거든
It was cheesecake. It was fine.
치즈케이크 맛이었고
맛은 괜찮았지
It had a buttery, crumbly,
graham cracker crust...
버터 맛에 바삭한
크래커 느낌의 빵에
with a very rich...
아주 풍부하면서도
yet light cream cheese filling.
부드러운 치즈크림
맛이 일품이었지
Wow, my whole mouth
just filled with saliva.
그냥 군침이
줄줄 흐른다
Know what? Forget it.
We're just hungry.
배가 고파서 그런 걸거야
We haven't had lunch.
We're just lightheaded.
점심을 안 먹어서
정신이 혼미한 거야
So let's go have lunch
and forget about the cheesecake.
치즈케이크는 잊고
점심이나 먹으러 가자
We'll drop it off
so we're not tempted.
갖다 주자
엉뚱한 맘 먹기 전에
-Where do you want to eat?
-Mama's Little Bakery, Chicago.
- 어디서 먹을까?
- 시카고에 있는 엄마 빵집
Mei Torme died.
멜 토메가 죽었네
Joey, that paper's like a year old.
조이, 그 신문
1년은 됐겠다
Does that mean the Sam Goody's sale
is over?
그럼 샘 구디즈
세일도 끝난 거겠네
So, I finally heard back
from Aunt Cheryl...
셰릴 숙모하고
통화를 해 봤는데
and apparently it wasn't a mistake.
착오가 아니라고 하시네
There's limited seating..
자리가 부족해서...
Limited seating? I am just
one tiny person!
자리가 부족해?
난 자리도 안 차지한다고!
Yeah, but she doesn't know that.
그렇지만 프래니는
그걸 모르잖아
I mean, the last time she saw you...
프래니가 아는
네 모습은
you'd have turned one of those
little wedding chairs into kindling.
피로연장 의자를
부셔버리기 충분했지
"Limited seating."
That's such a lame excuse.
'자리가 부족해'?
그럴듯한 걸 대던가
That's not the reason
she's not inviting me.
날 초대 안 하는
이유는 따로 있어
What's the big deal? I wasn't invited
to the ceremony, just the reception.
뭘 신경 써?
나도 피로연에만 초대받았어
If it makes you feel any better, Joan
and I will just make an appearance...
나도 사실은 조운과
얼굴만 살짝 비추고
and then we'll leave early
as a sign of protest.
항의의 뜻으로
일찍 나올 거야
-Joan?
-Yeah, my date.
- 조운?
- 같이 갈 여자야
Assistant professor in linguistics.
Tall, very beautiful.
언어학과의 조교수인데
키도 크고 아주 예뻐
And despite what some people say,
not broad-backed.
소문대로
등짝이 넓지도 않고 말야
Wait a minute.
You got "Ross Geller and Guest"?
잠깐만, 오빠말고
한 사람 더 초대했어?
I wasn't invited,
and you got "and Guest"?
난 초대도 못 받았는데
오빤 한 명 더 데려가?
Excuse me, I do have to interrupt
on Ross' behalf.
잠깐, 내가 로스 입장에서
한 마디 할게
I think the rule applies here.
규칙이 적용되는 상황이야
Since he has a chance
to get on broad-back..
로스가 등짝 넓은
여자와 잘...
Not broad-back!
안 넓다니까!
잠깐, 날 데리고 가
Wait a minute. You're bringing me.
조운 꼭 데려가야 돼
I can't cancel on Joan.
- 왜?
- 내 말 뭐 들은 거야?
-Why not?
-Did you not hear me?
언어학과의
조교수라고 했잖아
She's an assistant professor
in the linguistics department.
걔들이 얼마나
와일드한데
They're wild.
- 넌 왜 가고 싶은데?
- 그거야...
-Why do you want to come anyway?
-Because...
내 사촌이니까
she's my cousin.
같이 자랐으니까
I mean, we grew up together.
친척이잖아
그래서 그런 거야
Family, you know?
And all that's important to me.
좋아, 널 데려갈게
Okay, all right. I'll take you.
조운한테 전화할게
I'll go call Joan.
착하다
Oh, that's nice.
친척이라면 꼭 가야지
Family should be there.
걔 인생에서
가장 행복한 날이고
It's her wedding.
Happiest day of her life.
글쎄 두고 보라지
We'll see.
점심 고마웠어
Well, thank you for lunch.
네가 돈 낸 거 아냐?
Wait, I thought you paid.
요즘 우리 공짜로
먹는데 뭐 있다
Apparently, we don't pay
for food anymore.
- 저거 봤어?
- 아직 그대로 있네
-Do you see what I see?
-It's still there.
브레이버맨 부인
안 계신가봐
Mrs. Braverman must be out.
먼 데 갔을 수도 있지
몇 달 안 올 수도 있고
She could be out of town.
Maybe gone for months.
그럼 다 상할 텐데
상한 거 먹으면 안 되지
By then, it may spoil.
She can't come back to bad cheesecake.
- 죽을 수도 있어
- 그럼 안 되지
-It could kill her.
-Don't want that.
우리가 지켜주는 거야
We're protecting her.
- 가져가자
- 그럼 빨리 해
-We'll take it.
-But quick.
- 왜?
- 안에서 기척이 났거든
-Why?
-I hear her in there.
어서 가!
Go! Go! Go!
Oh, my God, that's David.
맙소사, 데이빗이야
-Who?
-David, the scientist guy.
- 누구?
- 데이빗, 그 과학자
David that I was in love with.
내가 사랑했던 그 데이빗
Who went to Russia
and broke my heart, David.
날 울리고 러시아로 간
그 데이빗 말야
Oh, my God!
세상에!
Say their name enough,
they turn around.
이름을 여러번 부르니
뒤돌아 보네
Phoebe.
피비
David.
데이빗
웬일이에요?
러시아에 있을 사람이?
What are you doing?
Aren't you supposed to be in Russia?
학술회 때문에
잠시 왔어요
I'm just in town for a conference.
좋아 보이네요
God, you look phenomenal.
뭐...
Well...
그래요
Yeah.
데이빗도 좋아 보여요
머리 잘랐어요?
You look great too.
Did you get a haircut?
네, 서른 번쯤요
Yeah. Well, I got like 30 of them.
고백할 게 있어요
Look, I got a confession to make.
피비를 만날까해서
여길 왔어요
I was hoping to run into you here.
며칠만 있다 갈 건데
괜히 성가시게 할까봐
I didn't know if I should call.
I was only in town a few days...
전화하기도 망설여졌어요
and I didn't want to intrude
on your life.
정말 보고 싶었는데
I really wanted to see you...
피비도 날 보고 싶어할 지
알 수 없어서
but I didn't know
if you wanted to see me.
물론 보고 싶어했죠
항상 생각했어요
Of course I would want to see you.
I think about you all the time.
그래요?
나도 늘 생각했거든요
Really? Because I think about you
all the time.
민스크에 피비 생각나게
만드는 동상이 있거든요
There's a statue in Minsk
that reminds me of you so much.
실은 레닌 동상인데
It's actually of Lenin...
어떤 각도에서 보면...
but, you know, at certain angles...
어쨌건, 오늘 저녁
같이 할래요?
Anyway, do you want
to have dinner tonight?
좋아요
Yes.
아, 안돼요!
Oh, no!
- 뭐라고요?
- 안되겠어요
-What?
-I can't.
약속이 있거든요
내일은 안될까요?
I can't believe I have plans.
Can you do it tomorrow?
아뇨, 몇 시간 후면 떠나요
밤 비행길 타거든요
No, I have to go in a few hours.
I have to be on the redeye.
그럼 혹시
민스크에 오게 되면...
Listen, next time you're in Minsk...
피비? 잠깐 얘기 좀 할까?
Phoebe? Can I talk to you
for a second?
무슨 짓이야?
What are you doing?
조이와 약속이 있어
I have plans with Joey.
그래서? 이해할 거야
So? He'll understand.
못할거야
그리고 그게 중요한 게 아냐
No, he won't.
And that's not even the point.
친구와의 약속을 어기면
안된다고 일장 연설을 했잖아
I made a whole speech about how
you do not cancel plans with friends.
그런데 내 평생의
사랑이 러시아에서
And now just because, potentially,
the love of my life...
하룻밤 지내려고
찾아왔는데
returns from Russia
for one night...
내 신념을 바꾸라고?
I should change my beliefs?
신념을 바꾸면 되겠다!
I should change my beliefs!
아냐, 원칙을 안 지키면
아무 것도 안 돼
No. If I don't have my principles,
I don't have anything.
의지력 대단하다
You're so strong.
아님 조이 만나 후딱
저녁 먹고 데이빗 만나야겠다
Or I should rush through dinner
with Joey and meet David at 9.
와, 정말 맛있다!
Oh, my God, that is so good!
배는 부른데
지금 그만 먹으면
I'm full. And yet I know
if I stop eating this...
후회할 거야
I'll regret it.
뭐 먹는 거야?
Hey, what have you got there?
이건...
Oh, it's...
두부 케이큰데 좀 줄까?
It's tofu cake. Want some?
오늘밤 뭐 해?
What are you doing tonight?
이봐, 이봐
Dude. Dude.
미안해
Sorry.
피비 만나잖아
I got plans with Phoebe.
그래? 피비 9시에
데이트 있다던데
Really? Monica said
she had a date at 9.
- 뭐? 오늘밤?
- 모니카가 그러던데
-What? Tonight?
-That's what Monica said.
나한데 일장연설을 해놓고
데이트를 한다고?
After that speech, she makes a date on
the same night she has plans with me?
빅 대디를
우습게 봐도 유분수지
She's trying to pull a fast one
on Big Daddy.
Here, I think this is us.
여기가 우리 자리야
Limited seating, my ass.
자리 부족한 거 좋아하네
Let's see who made the cut.
누가 초대받았나 볼까?
Hi. I'm Monica Geller.
안녕하세요
모니카 겔러예요
-How do you know the bride and groom?
-I worked with Frannie.
- 신랑 신부와 어떤 사이죠?
- 전에 프래니와 같이 일했죠
Used to work with her. Used to.
전에 같이 일했다
I'm a relative
and I didn't get invited.
전 친척인데
초대도 못 받았어요
A blood relative. Blood.
피를 나눈 친척이오
Stop saying "blood" to strangers.
'피'소리 좀 그만 할래
그쪽은요? 이 커플과는
어떻게 아는 사이죠?
And you? How do you know the couple?
We went to college with both of them.
대학 동창이었고
Now we live next door.
지금은 이웃에 살아요
Okay, you're fine.
좋아요, 그쪽은 봐주죠
-Are you guys ready?
-Yes.
- 준비됐어요?
- 네
전 그린 샐러드와
물이면 돼요
I'll have a green salad,
house dressing and water's fine.
손님은요?
And for you, sir?
네, 여기 천천히 구운 연어는
Yeah. This slow-roasted salmon...
얼마나 천천히 굽는 거죠?
how slow are we talking?
벌써 구워놓은 겁니다
It's already been roasted.
그럼 됐고
스페셜 다시 말해줄래요?
Oh, then no. Maybe I should hear
the specials again.
세 번이나 들었잖아
We've heard the specials three times.
프라임 갈비, 마히 마히
그리고 랍스터 라비올리잖아
There's prime rib, mahi-mahi
and a very special lobster ravioli.
- 그런데 라비올리가 떨어졌어요
- 그럼 다시 골라야겠네
-Actually, we're out of the ravioli.
-Well, that changes everything!
피비, 네 말이 옳았어
You know what, Phoebe?
You were right before.
친구란 소중한 거야
Friends are so important.
그래, 나 똑똑하잖아
나도 알아
Yeah, I'm very wise. I know.
내가 정말 하고 싶은 게
뭔지 알아?
Know what I really want?
- 뭔데?
- 길고 긴 대화
-What?
-Is to have a long, long talk.
있잖아, 조이의 속을
완전히 열어 보이는 거야
You know? Get Joey out on the
open road and really open him up.
- 결정하셨어요?
- 네
-Any progress?
-Yes.
전 랍스터로 할래요
I will have the lobster ravioli.
조이, 이러다 날 새겠다
God, Joey, this is taking forever.
- 급할 것도 없잖아
- 있지...
-What's the rush?
-Well...
나 약속 있어
I have an appointment.
아주 중요한 약속이야
And it's very important.
뭔데?
What is it?
사실은...
Well...
데이트야
it's a date.
데이트? 뭔가 착오겠지
친구와 약속이 있는 날
A date? No, you must be mistaken,
because you wouldn't have a date...
데이트 약속을
잡을 애가 아니잖아
on the same night
you have plans with a friend.
죄책감들게 하지 마
Don't make me feel badly.
아니, 할 거야!
No, I'm gonna!
나한텐 여자 만났다고
그렇게 쥐잡듯 해서
You made me feel really guilty
about going out with that girl.
날 아주 나쁜 놈 만들고
너도 똑같은 짓을 하잖아
Like I did something terrible.
Now you're doing the same thing.
아냐! 이건 달라!
It's not! It's totally different!
데이빗 만나는 거야
그 과학자 말야
This is with David.
Remember David, the scientist guy?
내겐 아주 특별한 사람이야
He's very special to me.
내가 만난 여자도 특별했어
그 여자도 과학자였고
My girl the other night was special.
She was a scientist too.
- 그랬어?
- 고등학교 졸업했으니까
-She was?
-Well, she graduated high school.
됐어, 신경 안 써
Whatever. Know what?
데이빗은 4시간 후면 떠나니까
만나러 갈 거야
He's only here for four
hours and I'm gonna go see him.
- 맘대로 해!
- 그럴 거야
-Fine!
-Yeah.
What are you still doing here?
I told you, lobster ravioli!
뭐하는 거예요?
랍스터 시켰잖아요
I was about to leave.
I didn't think you were coming.
안 오는 줄 알고
가려던 참이에요
I wouldn't have missed this.
어떻게 안 와요
Well, I'm very glad you're here.
와줘서 정말 기뻐요
Oh, you're such a gentleman.
정말 신사적이세요
Come on, we're going to my place.
우리 집으로 가요
Are you eating the cheesecake
without me?
나없이 혼자
치즈케이크 먹고 있어?
I will give you $100
to whistle right now.
지금 휘파람 불면
100달러 준다
-How can you eat it without me?
-What'll you do?
- 어떻게 혼자 먹니?
- 어쩔래?
Tell Monica or Joey?
No, you'd have to tell them everything.
모니카나 조이한테 이를래?
그럼 사실을 밝혀야 할 걸
We're dessert stealers.
We're living outside the law.
우린 도둑질이나 하는
무법자라고
I don't trust you with this cake.
널 못 믿겠다
I got it first,
and I'm taking it back!
내가 처음 발견했으니
도로 갖다 줄거야
-What? Oh, no.
-Oh, yes.
- 뭐? 안 돼
- 왜 안 돼?
You think I trust you with it?
내가 널 믿을 것 같아?
No, we'll split it.
우리 반씩 나누자
That's not fair. You had some.
불공평해, 넌 벌써 먹었잖아
I think Monica would be
very interested to know...
모니카가
네가 자기가 만든 케익을
that you called her cheesecake
"dry and mealy."
'건조하고 팍팍하다'고 했던 걸
알면 재밌겠다
뭘로 나누지?
What do we use to split it?
All right, pick a half.
좋아, 골라
Well, this side looks bigger.
이쪽이 커보이는데
But there's more crust on this side.
빵 부분은 이쪽이 많아
Maybe if I measure it..
잘 재 보면...
Pick a piece!
어서 골라!
-All right, I pick that one.
-It's the smaller piece.
- 알았어, 저거
- 그게 작은 건데
Okay. There you go.
자, 여기 있어
Enjoy your half, my friend.
But that is it.
맛있게 먹어
그게 다니까
No sharing, no switching,
and don't come crying to me...
나누기도 바꾸기도 없고
먼저 먹었다고
if you eat your piece too fast.
징징짜며 달라기도 없다
-You gonna give me some of yours?
-Oh, no.
- 네 거 좀 줄래?
- 안 되지
No switching, no sharing.
And don't come crying to me.
나누기도 바꾸기도
달라고 징징거리기도 없어
I may just sit here
and have my cake all day.
나 여기 앉아서
하루 종일 먹을까보다
Just sit here in the hallway
and eat my..
여기 복도에 앉아서
내 케이크를...
Ross, sweetheart!
로스, 왔구나!
Oh, hey, Aunt Millie.
안녕하세요, 밀리 숙모
-Isn't it a beautiful wedding?
-Yes, it is.
- 아름다운 결혼식이지?
- 네, 그러네요
Every time, on the lips!
왜 꼭 입술이야!
Why? Why on the lips?
왜! 왜 입술이냐고?
There's Frannie.
Won't she be happy to see me?
저기 프래니다
날 보면 좋아하겠지?
You be nice, all right?
너무 못돼게 굴지 마
I didn't bring you to ambush her.
그러라고 데려온 거
아니니까
Frannie was the one
who showed your Playboys to Mom.
프래니가 엄마한테 오빠
'플레이보이' 잡지 보여줬어
That bitch.
나쁜 계집애
Monica!
모니카!
What..?
어떻게...?
Am I doing here?
Surprised to see me?
어떻게 왔냐고?
왜, 놀랐어?
Ross brought me.
How do you like that?
로스가 데려왔지
기분 어때?
Hi, Frannie. Congratulations.
안녕, 프래니
결혼 축하해
You invite my whole family,
and not me? Why?
우리 가족을 초대하면서
왜 나만 쏙 뺐니? 왜?
Why wouldn't you want me here?
What could I have done?
왜 날 안 부른 거야?
내가 뭘 했길래
Stuart!
스튜어트!
I believe you know my husband.
우리 남편 알지?
So it's really a question
of "who" could you have done.
문제는 네가 '누구'와
뭘 했는가였어
I hate this, but I have to go.
가긴 싫지만 가야해요
I can't miss my flight.
비행기 놓치면 안되거든요
I bet there's
another flight to Minsk in..
민스크행 비행기는
또 있을...
July.
7월에 있어요
That's really beautiful.
What does it mean?
아름답네요
무슨 뜻이죠?
"Please clean my beakers."
'비커 좀 씻어주세요'
I don't get out of the lab much.
늘 실험실에만 있다보니
I thought it meant something else.
다른 뜻인 줄 알았어요
네, 사실은 다른 말을
Yeah, well, I really actually
wanted to say...
that.
하고 싶었는데
But I figured I probably shouldn't
because...
떠나야 할 사람이
해서는 안될 말이라고
I have to leave.
생각했거든요
No, you're right. Don't say it.
맞아요, 말하지 말아요
I do, though.
그래도 내 맘 알죠?
I do too.
그럼요
Well, bye, Phoebe.
잘 있어요, 피비
Now's not the time, Joey.
You can yell at me tomorrow.
지금은 제발 하지 마
소리지르려면 아침에 해
Wait, no, Phoebe.
I'm not gonna yell at you.
잠깐, 아니야 피비
소리 안 지를 거야
I just started thinking
about you and David...
너와 데이빗
생각하다가
and I remember how bummed you were
the first time he left.
데이빗 떠났을 때 네가
얼마나 상심했나 떠올랐어
Oh, Phoebe, come here.
피비, 이리 와
-Are you okay?
-No, I'm not okay.
- 괜찮아?
- 아니, 괜찮지 못해
The only guy I've ever been
crazy about is going to Minsk...
내가 유일하게 사랑한
남자가 민스크로 가는데
and I may never see him again.
다신 못 만날 지도 몰라
You could always visit him.
만나러 가면 되지
Right. Like they'll let me
have a passport.
그래, 비자를
잘도 내주겠다
Anything I can do? Whatever you need.
내가 해줄 일 없을까?
Well, now...
글쎄, 네가
if you achieve distillation of
subatomic particles before he does...
양자 미립자 증류법을
먼저 개발해내면
then he could come back.
돌아올 수도 있지
I could give it a shot.
한 번 해보지 뭐
Oh, look! There's a piece
that doesn't have floor on it.
봐! 저건 마루 바닥에
안 붙었는 걸
-Stick to your side!
-Come on, now!
- 네 쪽만 먹어!
- 그러지 마!
All right, what are we having?
뭐 먹는 거야?
Oh, wait, I forgot my wrap.
- 이런, 스카프 두고 왔다
- 알았어, 여기서 기다려
Okay, wait here.
Hi, sweetie! Are you leaving?
우리 귀염둥이, 이제 가게?
-Well..
-Give us a kiss. Come on.
- 그게...
- 뽀뽀해야지, 어서
Why? Why on the lips?
왜요? 왜 입술이냐고요?